<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<news>
    <source>
        <sourcename>WSJ</sourcename>
        <headline>Japan to Build Longer-Range Missiles and Study Hypersonic Technology
            Government seeks to expand military spending as it faces assertive China
        </headline>
        <passage>TOKYO—Japan’s Defense Ministry said Wednesday it wanted to start producing longer-range missiles and
            conduct research into hypersonic missile systems, a response to rising regional tensions including China’s
            threats against Taiwan.
            The ministry said it was planning to build two types of “standoff” missiles that can strike an enemy target
            from far away.
            Officials declined to give the exact range of the proposed new missiles or the range of current models. But
            their description suggested the government wanted to fill a gap in Japan’s current arsenal, which analysts
            say could strike ships or planes of an invader after it got close to Japanese shores, but not a missile base on
            Chinese or North Korean soil that was firing at Japan.
            The ministry said it wanted to start research into hypersonic missile systems, a term that generally refers
            to missiles that travel at least five times the speed of sound and can be maneuvered before hitting their
            target.
            Hypersonic missile tests by China, Russia and North Korea have raised U.S. concerns, and Russia said in
            August that it has used hypersonic missiles in its invasion of Ukraine.
            The Japanese Defense Ministry disclosed its missile plans as part of its budget request for the fiscal year
            beginning April 2023.
            Facing an increasingly assertive China, the government of Prime Minister Fumio Kishida has pledged to
            significantly boost Japan’s defense forces within five years. His ruling party has proposed lifting defense
            spending to 2% of gross domestic product after decades in which the figure was usually capped at 1%.
            Earlier this month, China’s military launched five missiles that landed inside Japan’s exclusive economic
            zone as a part of exercises simulating a blockade of Taiwan. Beijing was responding to a visit by House Speaker
            Nancy Pelosi to the self-governing island. China claims Taiwan as part of its territory and has threatened to
            capture the island by force.
            Mrs. Pelosi later visited Tokyo and met Mr. Kishida, who said they agreed that the U.S. and Japan should
            collaborate to preserve peace in the Taiwan Strait. National security adviser Jake Sullivan is meeting
            counterparts from Japan and South Korea in Honolulu on Thursday to discuss Indo-Pacific defense cooperation.
            The U.S., Japan’s principal ally, has long pushed Tokyo to increase its defense spending and take a greater
            role in helping support American military operations in East Asia.
            “We will make extensive efforts to secure the budget to radically strengthen our country’s defense
            capabilities,” said Japan’s new defense minister, Yasukazu Hamada, at a meeting of ruling-party lawmakers in
            August.
            Japan has traditionally avoided acquiring weapons that can attack other countries because of its
            constitution, which renounces war. But in recent years ruling-party lawmakers and the late Prime Minister Shinzo Abe have
            advocated revising that principle in cases where Japan believes it is about to be attacked by an enemy.
            A new defense strategy to be adopted by the end of the year is expected to clarify the government’s position
            on strike capability.
            One of the longer-range standoff missiles described in the Defense Ministry’s request is an improved version
            of an existing surface-to-ship missile known as Type 12. The ministry said it was also developing versions that
            could be launched from ships or planes.
            Another missile slated for mass production is called a hypervelocity gliding projectile, which is more
            maneuverable than other missiles although the technology is still in the early stages.
            In addition to China, Japan is concerned about Russia and North Korea. Moscow has built closer ties with
            Beijing this year. Chinese and Russian bombers carried out a joint exercise near Japan during President Biden’s
            visit to Tokyo in May.
            North Korea has fired missiles at least 17 times this year, according to Japan’s Defense Ministry, and
            officials say Pyongyang has tested various methods, including firing them from railcars and submarines.
        </passage>
    </source>

    <source>
        <sourcename>Reuters</sourcename>
        <headline>Japan plans to develop longer-range missiles to counter China, Russia - By Tim Kelly
        </headline>
        <passage>TOKYO, Aug 31 (Reuters) - Japan will develop and mass produce a cruise missile and a high-velocity
            ballistic missile, it said on Wednesday, as it seeks the ability to strike more distant targets as part of a
            military expansion aimed at meeting threats from China and Russia.
            The procurement plan unveiled in the Ministry of Defence's annual budget request represents a clear
            departure from a decades-long range limit imposed on Japan's constitutionally constrained Self Defence
            Forces, that meant they could only field missiles with ranges of a few hundred kilometres.

            "China continues to threaten to use force to unilaterally change the status quo and is deepening its
            alliance with Russia," the ministry said in its budget request.
            "It is also applying pressure around Taiwan with supposed military exercises and has not renounced the use
            of military force as a way to unite Taiwan with the rest of China," it said.
            Alarm about China's regional ambitions grew this month after it fired five ballistic missiles into waters
            less than 160 km (100 miles) from Japan in a show of force after U.S. House of Representatives Speaker Nancy
            Pelosi's visited Taiwan.

            The ministry also mentioned North Korea as a threat to Japan.
            The budget request is for funding to mass produce ground-launched cruise missiles, an extended range version
            of the Mitsubishi Heavy Industries (7011.T) designed Type 12 missile already in use, to strike ships, and a
            new, high-velocity glide ballistic missiles capable of hitting ground targets.
            The ministry is also seeking money to develop other projectiles, including hypersonic warheads.
            The ministry did not give a range for the proposed weapons, or say how many it planned to field, but they
            would likely be able to reach targets in mainland China if deployed along Japan's nearby southwest Okinawa
            island chain.
            Japan has already ordered air-launched missiles, including the Joint Strike Missile (JSM) made by Norway's
            Kongsberg (KOG.OL), and Lockheed Martin Corp's (LMT.N) Joint Air-to-Surface Stand-Off Missile (JASSM) with a
            range of up to 1,000 km (620 miles).
            Unlike with ship or ground-based launchers, however, the number it can fire is limited by how many planes it
            can put in the air to fire them.
            The ministry asked for a 3.6% increase in spending to 5.6 trillion yen ($39.78 billion) for the year
            starting on April 1, but said the figure would rise after it calculated the cost of new procurement
            programmes.
            Prime Minister Fumio Kishida's government will approve that increased request at the end of the year when it
            will also unveil a major defence strategy overhaul and new midterm military buildup plan.
            Kishida, who has described security in East Asia as "fragile" after Russia's invasion of Ukraine, has
            promised to "substantially" increase defence outlays to prepare Japan for regional conflict.
            His ruling Liberal Democratic Party in its upper house election manifesto in July promised to double defence
            spending to 2% of gross domestic product over five years.
            That would make Japan the world's third biggest military spender behind major ally the United States, and
            neighbouring China.
            In addition to increasing stockpile of missiles and other munitions, Japan's military wants to develop its
            cyber defences, electromagnetic warfare capabilities and space presence.
        </passage>
    </source>

    <source>
        <sourcename>Eurasiantimes</sourcename>
        <headline>Japan Is Pushing For Highest Ever Defense Budget; Eyes Hypersonic Tech, Long-Range Missiles and Drones
            To Counter China
            By Sakshi Tiwari
        </headline>
        <passage>Japan’s Defense Minister Yasukazu Hamada recently iterated that Tokyo had entered a new era of crisis,
            advising the country to rethink its security approach amid exacerbated military threats from China, Russia,
            and North Korea.
            Against that backdrop, the Asian country is exploring hypersonic technology and upgrading its missile
            capability.
            On August 31, Japan’s Defense Ministry made its largest ever budget request of a whopping 5.6 trillion yen
            ($58.7 billion) for the year ending March 2024, in contrast to 5.4 trillion yen for the current fiscal year.
            When additional requests for military equipment are considered, the final budget will top at least 6
            trillion, according to people with knowledge of internal ministerial discussions. These requests will be
            made at the end of 2022 when Japan will release a new national security strategy and defense guidelines.
            The budget request comes after a Japanese government panel finalized a list of research areas eligible for
            funding support in economic security, including the development of drones and hypersonic technology. Tokyo’s
            three notable adversaries – China, Russia, and probably even North Korea, possess hypersonic missiles.
            The expert government panel approved 27 applications categorized among maritime activities, aerospace,
            cyberspace, and bio-related fields. The critical technologies include artificial intelligence, robotics, and
            quantum technology.
            The funding will specifically go toward satellite constellation technology, which processes data through a
            network of smaller satellites. It is pertinent to note that there were reports last year suggesting that the
            Japanese government had decided to establish a network of satellites for tracking hypersonic missiles.
            The situation has changed tremendously since then. Over a month into the invasion, the Russian Defense
            Ministry revealed that it had used a hypersonic missile ‘Kinzhal’ to hit a target in Ukraine. There are
            speculations that North Korea, located close to Japan, had also developed hypersonic weapons.
            Not just that, as part of training for a blockade of Taiwan following Nancy Pelosi’s visit, China’s military
            fired five missiles that landed inside Japan’s exclusive economic zone. Japan’s geographical proximity to
            Taiwan could jeopardize its security in case of a Chinese invasion.
            While the country has chosen to remain pacifist, focusing solely on its territorial defense, the military
            threats posed by the ‘Big 3’ have given way to a tectonic shift in its military posture.
            Japan’s Focus On Military Tech, Better Fire Power
            It is no surprise that Tokyo has decided to pay special attention to hypersonic technology, given the threat
            posed by Chinese and Russian hypersonic missiles. The ministry intends to increase the number of
            early-warning aircraft and improve the performance of radar site systems to strengthen defense against
            hypersonic missiles.
            According to the sources contacted by a Japan and Korea tracking publication, The Asahi Shimbun, the
            ministry is also attempting to improve the missile intercept command system known as the Japan Aerospace
            Defense Ground Environment to run the country’s two-stage missile defense effectively.

            The Japanese Defense Ministry has not revealed the purpose behind the satellite constellation it wants to
            put together. However, it is speculated to be a system for detecting and tracking hypersonic missiles that
            are otherwise capable of evading missile defense systems like Aegis, used by Japan’s Self Defense Forces.
            In January this year, it was revealed that Japan had decided to develop electromagnetic ‘rail guns’ to
            intercept highly maneuverable hostile hypersonic missiles.
            Besides hypersonic technology, the Japanese Defense Ministry has ambitious plans for developing and using
            Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAVs).
            The expert panel announced that funding would be available for the development of unmanned, autonomous
            probes for ocean observation. The development of AI-powered cyber security will also receive government
            backing.
            This becomes paramount as there has been enhanced movement and presence of Chinese and Russian vessels in
            Japan’s waters. Both China and Russia have territorial disputes with Tokyo. Japan announced that PLA and
            Russian warships were encircling it not long ago, and drones would certainly boost Japan’s surveillance
            capabilities.
            In reaction to escalating regional tensions, the Japanese Defense Ministry also announced its plans to
            produce longer-range missiles. The ministry declared that it intended to create two different kinds of
            “standoff” missiles capable of launching attacks from a great distance.
            The precise range of the new missiles that have been planned or the range of the existing types was withheld
            by officials. However, their explanation suggested that the government wanted to fill a gap in Japan’s
            current arsenal.
            Analysts and military observers have long maintained that the Japanese missiles could hit an invading
            force’s ships or planes after they came within striking distance of Japanese shores but not a missile base
            on Chinese or North Korean soil that was firing at Japan.
            The cabinet will review the expert panel’s suggestions before deciding whether to implement them or not.
            Tokyo will begin hiring researchers later this year, and investigations are expected to start in March 2023.
            Prime Minister Fumio Kishida’s government has vowed to strengthen Japan’s defense capabilities within five
            years. After decades in which the amount was typically capped at 1%, his ruling party has proposed raising
            defense spending to 2% of gross domestic product.
        </passage>
    </source>


    <source>
        <sourcename>Asahi</sourcename>
        <headline>Japan plans to upgrade defense for hypersonic missiles
            By KAIGO NARISAWA/ Staff Writer

        </headline>
        <passage>A projectile that North Korea’s Academy of National Defense Science called a hypersonic missile is test
            launched on Jan. 5. The image was dispatched by the Korean Central News Agency. (Provided by the Korea News
            Service)
            The Defense Ministry’s budget requests for fiscal 2023 will include funds to strengthen Japan’s capability
            to detect and intercept hypersonic missiles, which are more elusive than conventional missiles, government
            sources said.
            The project will be one of more than 100 items the ministry is expected to pursue without specifying costs.
            North Korea earlier this year reportedly conducted tests that included hypersonic missiles, raising a sense
            of urgency in Japan to bolster defense against such weapons.
            Compared with conventional missiles, hypersonic missiles are more dangerous because they can travel at more
            than five times the speed of sound, or Mach 5, which is about 6,000 kph.
            They can also fly at a low altitude, making them less vulnerable to detection by radar and other
            surveillance systems. They can also travel on irregular trajectories, such ascending and descending, as
            opposed to the predictable travel paths of ballistic missiles.
            North Korea test-fired what it claimed were hypersonic mid-range missiles on Jan. 5 and Jan. 11. The
            projectiles apparently landed outside Japan’s exclusive economic zone.
            The launches raised concerns among Japanese officials because of the difficulties in intercepting hypersonic
            missiles targeting Japan.
            If missiles are fired by a neighboring country toward Japan, the Self-Defense Forces would track them
            through radar systems placed across the country as well as early-warning aircraft equipped with
            sophisticated radars until they near Japanese territories.
            If the SDF determines that the projectiles would land on Japanese territory, interceptor missiles carried by
            Aegis system-equipped ships would be deployed to shoot them down outside the Earth’s atmosphere.
            If interception fails at this stage, land-based missiles would be launched to intercept the threat near
            Japan’s ground surface.
            To bolster defense against hypersonic missiles, the ministry plans to upgrade the performance of radar site
            systems and introduce more early-warning aircraft.
            The ministry is also trying to enhance the capability of the missile intercept command system known as the
            Japan Aerospace Defense Ground Environment to efficiently operate the nation’s two-stage missile defense,
            along with the acquisition of additional missiles, according to the sources.
            Hypersonic missiles come in two types: hypersonic cruise missiles (HCM) powered by engines; and hypersonic
            glide vehicles (HGV), which glide to their targets after being launched from rocket boosters.
            Russia and China are ahead of other countries in HGV technology, according to defense experts.
            Japan plans to introduce a missile defense system that can deal with HGVs to future Aegis ships, the sources
            said.
        </passage>
    </source>

    <source>
        <sourcename>Dailyinformat</sourcename>
        <headline>Japan to Build Longer-Range Missiles and Study Hypersonic Technology
        </headline>
        <passage>TOKYO—Japan’s Protection Ministry mentioned Wednesday it wished to start out producing longer-range
            missiles and conduct analysis into hypersonic missile techniques, a response to rising regional tensions
            together with China’s threats in opposition to Taiwan.
            The ministry mentioned it was planning to construct two sorts of “standoff” missiles that may strike an
            enemy goal from distant.
        </passage>
    </source>


    <source>
        <sourcename>Japantimes</sourcename>
        <headline>Japan advances hypersonics research with combustion flight test
        </headline>
        <passage>Tokyo’s efforts to develop hypersonic aircraft and weapons reached a milestone Sunday, when the Japan
            Aerospace Exploration Agency (JAXA) successfully conducted its first combustion flight test using a device
            designed to gather critical data for the development of a scramjet engine.
            The device was carried in the nose of a test rocket launched into space at 5 a.m. from JAXA’s Uchinoura
            Space Center in Kagoshima Prefecture. The 9.15-meter-long S-520-RD1 rocket released the device about 3½
            minutes into the launch at an altitude of 168 kilometers. The combustion test was conducted for about six
            seconds at an altitude of approximately 30 km as the device was returning to Earth.
            According to JAXA officials, the data collected from the trial will be used in wind tunnel testing, with
            Japan aiming to flight-test a real engine during the next launch.
            The test, which is part of a project by the Defense Ministry’s Acquisition, Technology and Logistics Agency
            (ATLA), is aimed at researching and developing scramjet engine technologies that will allow aircraft and
            weapons to fly at hypersonic speeds — equivalent to at least five times the speed of sound. One of the
            planned military applications of this technology is the development of a hypersonic cruise missile (HCM).
            A scramjet engine draws the oxygen needed for combustion from the air, thereby making it suitable for
            powered hypersonic flight within the Earth’s atmosphere and avoiding the need for it to carry liquid oxygen.
            According to documentation provided by ATLA, these systems are expected to use dual-mode scramjet systems —
            a combination of ramjet and scramjet engines, the former of which are used to power vehicles at subsonic and
            supersonic speeds, while the latter achieve hypersonic speeds.
            Japan outlined its plan to develop and acquire highly maneuverable hypersonic weapons about three years ago,
            amid Tokyo’s concerns over the growing military capabilities of neighboring countries such as China and
            North Korea.
            “Japan is looking to acquire a ‘stand-off defensive attack capability’ in two development stages, the first
            of which will focus on the development of components and technologies related to the weapon’s warhead,
            airframe as well as fire-control, guidance and propulsion systems,” said Tokyo-based defense expert Kosuke
            Takahashi. The second stage will involve using the results from the first stage to test and evaluate the
            weapon and its capabilities, he added.
            According to a 2019 timeline provided by the Defense Ministry, Japan intends to field this missile in about
            2030, followed by an improved version by 2038, Takahashi said. However, the ministry has cautioned that this
            timeline is tentative, pointing out that Japan would “endeavor to obtain the technologies earlier.”
            HCMs are not the only defense project set to benefit from Japan’s research on hypersonics.
            Tokyo recently began work on a so-called hypervelocity gliding projectile (HVGP). The weapon — which is
            expected to have a range of at least several hundred kilometers — is designed for launch using a rocket
            motor, with the projectile, or glide vehicle, separating from it at a high altitude and then gliding at
            hypersonic speeds to its target, Takahashi noted.
            The HVGP, which is intended to be used in defending Japan’s remote southwestern islands, will be developed
            in two variants — Block I and Block II — with the latter featuring higher speed and maneuverability,
            according to ATLA.
            “Japan is anxious to catch up with countries such as Russia and China, both of which are making rapid
            progress with their hypersonic weapon programs,” said Takahashi.
            China fielded its first missile equipped with a hypersonic glide vehicle in 2020, according to the Pentagon,
            and has greatly advanced its scramjet engine development.
            The United States, Japan’s ally, is also making progress in this field, with the Pentagon announcing earlier
            this month that it successfully tested two Lockheed Martin test vehicles for the Air-Launched Rapid Response
            Weapon hypersonic missile.
            At the same time, Tokyo is working on capabilities to protect the country from such weapons. In fact, Japan
            and the U.S. agreed to deepen cooperation on emerging military technologies, including on finding ways to
            counter hypersonic missiles, as part of a pact signed in January.
            The deal includes provisions for joint research, development and production projects in military
            technologies ranging from hypersonic missiles to space-based defense capabilities.
            The provisions are aimed at “strengthening the defense capabilities and securing the technological
            superiority of the Japan-U.S. alliance,” while at the same time improving interoperability between allied
            forces, according to Japan’s Foreign Ministry.
            In its annual economic policy road map released last month, the Japanese government said it would aim to
            drastically boost defense spending “within the next five years.”
            Among other things, Tokyo is prioritizing the development of advanced technologies such as electromagnetic
            railguns — high-power microwave- and laser-based weapon systems — to help counter the growing missile threat
            posed by neighboring countries amid what the Defense Ministry calls an “increasingly severe security
            environment” around Japan.
        </passage>
    </source>

    <source>
        <sourcename>Chinadaily</sourcename>
        <headline>Japan military upgrade plans spark concerns for Asia security, experts say

        </headline>
        <passage>Reports that Japan may deploy long-range missiles to counter China have alarmed experts, who say the
            country is aggressively moving away from peaceful development and its pacifist Constitution.
            The Yomiuri Shimbun newspaper on Sunday reported that Japan is seeking to deploy 1,000 long-range missiles
            in addition to its stockpile of anti-ballistic missiles to boost its counterattack capability against China,
            citing unidentified government sources.
            The report is significant because Japan's pacifist Constitution forbids it from having weapons that can
            strike targets on foreign soil. A source quoted in the report directly named China as the reason for the
            deployment of such missiles. Officials are usually more guarded on linking upgrades in military capabilities
            to Japan's perceived concerns over China.
            "This is a very regrettable signal," said Atsushi Koketsu, emeritus professor at Yamaguchi University of
            Japan. Adherence to the pacifist Constitution and striving to achieve historical reconciliation with China,
            South Korea and other Asian neighbors should be a priority of Japan, the scholar said.
            Koketsu said Japan's past militarism had caused great harm to its Asian neighbors and to Japanese as well.
            Only by correctly understanding its history of aggression can Japan avoid repeating the same mistakes.
            "However, since the end of World War II, Japan has never truly completed the task of reflecting on its
            historical guilt," Koketsu said. "The Japanese government has not yet fully realized that Japan should bear
            the historical responsibility for launching wars and colonial rule.
            "The right-wing conservatives intensified the situation as they continue to spread the wrong historical
            cognition of denying the war of aggression in Japanese society while demanding the revision of the pacifist
            Constitution. They also hope to follow the United States and engage in major power confrontations in the
            region."
            Koketsu said Japan's heavy bet on its alliance with the US and its strategy of moving closer to NATO has
            created the potential for war in the Asia-Pacific region.
            "Japan is an Asian country and has the responsibility to maintain peace and stability in the Asian region,"
            Koketsu said. "The stability of the relationship between Japan and China is crucial to creating a peaceful
            future in Asia, and countries in the region also want this."
            Lan Shunzheng, a member of the Chinese Institute of Command and Control, a think tank on defense and
            military technology based in Beijing, said the reports of Japan's missile plans are jangling nerves in
            neighboring countries.
            Of Japan's reported missile plans, Lan said: "Japan is pursuing a greater military presence. If this time it
            succeeds, it will deploy more. If it keeps doing so, a new arms race could be triggered, bringing more chaos
            into the region."
            Lan said the reports also signaled Japan's long-term pursuit of military expansion, especially when it comes
            to offensive weapons.
            "It not only violates the spirit of its pacifist Constitution, but also ratchets up geopolitical tensions,"
            Lan said.
        </passage>
    </source>

    <source>
        <sourcename>Aljazeera</sourcename>
        <headline>Japan plans longer-range missiles to counter China, Russia
            Japan has become increasingly alarmed about China and Russia’s ambitions amid a number of territorial
            disputes.

        </headline>
        <passage>Japan says it will develop and mass-produce a cruise missile and a high-velocity ballistic missile, as
            part of a military expansion aimed at dealing with threats from China and Russia.
            The procurement plan unveiled in the defence ministry’s annual budget request on Wednesday was short on
            detail but represents a clear departure from a decades-long range limit imposed on Japan’s
            constitutionally-constrained Self-Defense Force.
            “China continues to threaten to use force to unilaterally change the status quo and is deepening its
            alliance with Russia,” the ministry said in its budget request.
            “It is also applying pressure around Taiwan with supposed military exercises and has not renounced the use
            of military force as a way to unite Taiwan with the rest of China,” it said.
            Alarm about China’s regional ambitions has intensified after it held large-scale military exercises that
            included firing ballistic missiles after US House of Representatives Speaker Nancy Pelosi visited Taiwan
            earlier this month. Five of the missiles landed in waters less than 160km (100 miles) from Japan.
            Tokyo also has long-running territorial disputes with Beijing and Moscow – over the Senkaku Islands, known
            as Diaoyu in China, and the Northern Territories, known as the Kuril islands in Russia.
            The defence ministry also mentioned the risk to Japan posed by North Korea, which has carried out an
            unprecedented number of weapons tests this year.
            The ministry said it will only be able to release details of the spending after December when the government
            is due to adopt a new national security strategy, which is being revised to reinforce Japan’s military
            capability over the next five years.
            Japan has already been strengthening its security alliance with the United States, a key ally, and expanding
            military cooperation with friendly nations in the Asia-Pacific region and Europe.
            Critics worry the missile upgrades – and the potential use of preemptive attacks – would fundamentally
            change Japan’s defence policy and potentially breach the post-war pacifist Constitution that limits the use
            of force to self-defence.
            Only a partial sum of 5.6 trillion yen ($40.4bn) was disclosed for 2023, but the ministry’s budget plan
            could rise to about 6.5 trillion yen ($47bn), up 20 percent from this year, Japanese media said.
            Japan caps annual defence spending at 1 percent of its GDP, but Kishida’s governing party proposes doubling
            that in coming years, citing NATO’s standard of 2 percent of GDP. That would make Japan the world’s
            third-biggest military spender after the US and China.
            The ministry requested an undisclosed amount to improve and mass-produce an upgraded Type 12 surface-to-ship
            guided missile to extend its range for use as “stand-off” attacks on enemy targets from destroyers and
            fighter jets.

            It has already ordered air-launched missiles, including the Norwegian-made Joint Strike Missile (JSM) and
            the US-manufactured Joint Air-to-Surface Stand-Off Missile (JASSM) with a range of up to 1,000km (620
            miles).
            The ministry also requested an undisclosed amount for development and mass production of a “high-speed
            gliding vehicle” to defend remote islands, including Okinawa and outer islands near Taiwan.
        </passage>
    </source>


    <source>
        <sourcename>Taipeitimes</sourcename>
        <headline>Japan considers deploying long-range missiles

        </headline>
        <passage>Japan is considering the deployment of more than 1,000 long-range cruise missiles to increase its
            ability to counter growing regional threats from China, the Yomiuri Shimbun reported yesterday.
            The country plans to upgrade its existing surface-to-ship missiles to extend their range from 100km to about
            1,000km, which would be enough to reach Chinese coastal areas, as well as North Korea, the newspaper
            reported, citing unnamed sources.
            Upgrades would also need to be made to enable Japan’s ships and aircraft to be able to fire the new
            missiles, which could hit land-based targets, the newspaper reported.
            The missiles would be deployed in and around the southwestern Kyushu region and on the small islands that
            dot Japan’s southwestern waters near Taiwan, the Yomiuri reported.
            Japanese officials could not be reached for comment.
            The plan is part of Japan’s attempt to narrow its missile capacity gap with China, while also addressing
            threats from North Korea, the newspaper said.
            Japan’s military is not officially recognized under the country’s post-war constitution and defense spending
            is limited to funding nominally defensive capabilities.
            Recent geopolitical tensions, including Russia’s invasion of Ukraine and China’s increasingly aggressive
            stance toward Taiwan, have prompted growing calls in Japan to review defense programs.
            Regional tensions ratcheted up this month after a visit by US House of Representatives Speaker Nancy Pelosi
            to Taiwan. In response, Beijing launched missiles over Taiwan and into Japan’s exclusive economic zone.
            Japanese Prime Minister Fumio Kishida has vowed to significantly boost defense spending, which has been kept
            near 1 percent of GDP.
            Local media also reported that the Japanese Ministry of Defense is likely to request ￥5.5 trillion (US$40.2
            billion) for the next fiscal year, up slightly from the ￥5.18 trillion requested for this fiscal year.
            However, the ministry was also expected to ask approval for a list of unpriced items, including the
            development cost to upgrade the long-range cruise missiles, the Asahi Shimbun reported.

        </passage>
    </source>
</news>